Denis V. Aleksandrov

Adobe Commerce (Magento) Developer

denis.v.aleksandrov@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/denal05/ https://denal05.github.io/ https://github.com/denal05/ +389 77 975812 Skopje, Karposh, 1000, North Macedonia

25+ years of IT experience. Medior Magento developer. A well-organized software engineer. Developed Magento 2 e-commerce shops, LAMP-stack web apps, iOS mobile apps, Java enterprise apps, and embedded systems firmware. Had a role in two FDA-certified medical devices.

Work Experience

MAGENTO 2 DEVELOPER

Nov 2023 - Aug 2024

SYNCIT GROUP | remote

Delivered Magento upgrades, created Docker environments, and removed malware.

- Upgraded Magento websites of existing production environments from 2.3/2.4 to 2.6/2.7
- Created various Docker environments for Magento 2
- Detected and removed malware
- Customized the classic Magento 2 multi-page checkout

MAGENTO 2 DEVELOPER

Feb 2023 - Jun 2023

NTT DATA SPAIN | remote

Wrote modules according to user stories and provided defect fixes in staging and production environments.

- Worked extensively on the "bulk order status update" functionality
- Integrated Algolia search
- Customized the "onepage" checkout
- Recommendation by Gerald Pesjak, Tech Lead at Technology Everywhere: "I appreciated your good vibes and good
 quality of code working with you as a developer in an ecommerce solution for Orange Belgium. You have an
 excellent team spirit and were always open to give others a helping hand if needed. Your understanding of
 magento2 is very good and your quality of code is well considering the PSR standards. I recommend working with
 Denis in a magento2 project as a developer."

MAGENTO 2 TECH SUPPORT ENGINEER

Jun 2021 - Dec 2022

ON TAP GROUP | remote

Provided first-tier technical support to e-commerce clients via the help desk and live chat, covering products and services, triaging issues, and providing partial or full solutions. The products included extensions for Magento 2, OpenCart, PrestaShop, and WooCommerce.

PROJECT LEAD & MAGENTO 2 DEVELOPER

Dec 2018 - Apr 2021

<u>CODEWELL UNLIMITED DOO</u> | North Macedonia

Responsible for project management using Scrumban. Developed both backend and frontend Magento 2 modules, running on AWS EC2. For more information regarding these projects, please see https://denal05.github.io

- Developed the e-commerce of a book publisher's e-book system.
- Developed kids' merchandise shop

PROJECT MANAGER

Mar 2011 - Oct 2018

INFORM DOO | North Macedonia

Responsible mostly for project management. Other responsibilities included regulatory compliance, quality assurance, technical writing, software development, system administration, operations, procurement, human resources, and

corporate social responsibility. Between 2011 and 2018, major clients were IntriCon Micromedical Technology, Gauge Telematics, and SnapBar.

Recommendation by Bryan Brenchley, Mentor for New Business & Tech Startups: "Denis worked for me at INform
for over 7 1/2 years. He was always ready to work above and beyond. He worked in many capacities - QA, Project
Management, Customer Service, and Software Development. His attention to detail was helpful in all job capacities.
Our clients spoke highly of his organizational and communication skills. He is a team player with a positive attitude. I
gladly recommend Denis..."

JUNIOR DEVELOPER | JUNIOR TESTER | CONFIGURATION MANAGER

Feb 2009 - Mar 2011

<u>Seavus (acquired by Qinshift)</u> | North Macedonia

Studied the ARM RISC microcontroller architecture (ARMv4x - ARMv8x). Utilized working procedures and protocols fundamental to source code development within Seavus. Performed software testing and Configuration Management for production releases as part of Quality Assurance.

COMPUTER SCIENCE TEACHER

Sep 2007 - Apr 2008

MOREAU CATHOLIC HIGH SCHOOL | Hayward, California, USA

Instructed students on three subjects: Advanced Placement Computer Science for the College Board AP CS A exam, Introduction to Computer Science using Java, and Computer Essentials with Microsoft Office. Clarified fundamental Computer Science concepts. Encouraged discipline, diligence, and design.

APPLICATION ENGINEER

May 2007 - Oct 2007

MOVELL SOFTWARE, INC. | Hayward, California, USA

Integrated weekly source code releases of Movell's real-time remote diagnostic software engine I-DEAL onto a development board running embedded Linux using the GNU ARM toolchain. Demonstrated the diagnostic software to potential customers.

ENTRY-LEVEL JAVA DEVELOPER

Jan 2007 - Apr 2007

DIVVIO | Hayward, California, USA

Coordinated release builds, extended functionality of media player integration, and implemented new features of the flagship product: a Web2.0 application video/audio aggregator.

Apr 2005 - Dec 2005

NORMAN CHRYSLER JEEP DODGE | Norman, Oklahoma, USA

Single-handedly maintained and expanded the entire IT infrastructure (including desktops, servers, databases, and networking equipment) of a major automobile dealership with three satellite offices. Made decisions in purchasing and coordinating with technology goods and services. Involved with all aspects of security.

MICROCOMPUTER LAB TECHNICIAN (HELP DESK)

Apr 2000 - Oct 2003

Office of IT at the University of Central Oklahoma | Edmond, Oklahoma, USA

Assisted Technology Support with work orders, including PC rebuilds/installation/removal/upgrades and basic and intermediate troubleshooting. Helped with the disposition of surplus computer equipment, including destroying data, salvaging parts, and rebuilding PCs. Checked IT computer labs and delivered printer supplies as needed.

Projects

Extra Blog module for Magento 2

Oct 2023 - Oct 2023

An extra Magento 2 module, with plugins for the "Blog" module, built as an exercise for the M.academy "Magento 2 Coding Kickstart" course by Mark Shust.

Blog module for Magento 2

A Magento 2 module built as an exercise for the M.academy "Magento 2 Coding Kickstart" course by Mark Shust with additional functionality.

docker-compose-plain-vanilla-magento-2.4

Nov 2023 - Aug 2024

Configuration files for a Docker container running plain-vanilla Magento Open Source 2.4

SwiftOtterOrderExport

Oct 2023 - Present

A Magento 2 module built as an exercise for the SwiftOtter "Prep Course for Adobe Certified Professional Developer (AD0-E702)" by Joseph Maxwell.

Volunteer Experience

Localization Volunteer (Macedonian language)

Jul 2011 - Present

YouVersion

Faithfully serving as a volunteer on the team that localizes the most popular Bible app for iOS, Android, and web into the Macedonian language.

Financial Officer Jul 2013 - Oct 2017

SEAM (IFES/InterVarsity in North Macedonia)

Responsible for finances, from paying bills and taxes to planning annual budgets, fundraising, grant proposals, and coordinating with the certified public accountant and financial officers of the umbrella organization International Fellowship of Evangelical Students (IFES/InterVarsity).

Team Member Oct 2010 - Jun 2013

HBM (CBMC in North Macedonia)

Participated in the Christian Business Network in North Macedonia - a marketplace ministry.

Core Skills

E-commerce Development: Magento 2, Malware detection and removal, Docker, PHP, MySQL, JavaScript, KnockoutJS, jQuery, Linux, Apache, Nginx, payment gateways, Postman, PhpStorm, REST API

Web Development: LAMP, Java, SQL, git, Tomcat, HTML, Node.js, CSS, Bootstrap, TypeScript, AWS, Express.js

Project Management: Jira, Gitlab, Bitbucket

iOS App Development: Swift, SwiftUI, Objective-C, SQLite, Firebase, Realm Database, Bluetooth Low Energy (BLE),

Core ML, Core Bluetooth, Core Data, Core Location, Create ML, Xcode

Desktop App Development: C++, Qt

Embedded Systems: C, Perl, Arduino, ARM microcontrollers, IAR Embedded Workbench

Education

Northwestern Polytechnic University (now San Francisco Bay University)

May 2006 - Apr 2008

Master of Science Electrical Engineering

University of Central Oklahoma

Dec 1999 - Apr 2005

Bachelor of Science Computer Science

Minor: Engineering Physics

Languages

English (fluent), Serbian (intermediate), Croatian (intermediate), Bulgarian (intermediate), Albanian (basic)

Certificates

Transform Magento 2 Admin Grids & Forms (Credential ID cert_c15w41wz) M.academy	Oct 2023
Magento 2 Coding Kickstart (Credential ID cert_jp1pmr3t) M.academy	Sep 2023
iOS & Swift - The Complete iOS App Development Bootcamp Udemy	Jan 2021
Swift 4 Fundamentals Sololearn	Oct 2018
iOS Advanced Training in Objective-C Seavus Education and Development Center	Jul 2016
iOS Basic Training in Objective-C Seavus Education and Development Center	Jun 2016
Sun Microsystems Certified Java Programmer for the Java 2 Platform 1.4 - 06/05/2006 Sun Microsystems	Jun 2006

Interests

hiking, Baroque music, Jazz, Blues, Ethno music, Tango Nuevo, Progressive Rock, Electronic music, Gospel music, Worship